#Encodergasm Presents
～
Space travel log 0968.
（ジェット）宇宙航海日誌０９６８
We were wasting our free time.
われわれは空虚な時を過ごしていた
It sounds good to call the bounty-hunting job a "freelance" job...
賞金稼ぎの仕事はフリーランス
といえば聞こえはいいが―
...but all that means is that we're self-employed.
要するに自由業であり
仕事がないときは全然ないのである
When we have no jobs, we have none at all.
Well, that's all a part of our destiny...
まあ これも運命なんだが―
金がないのは困るのである
...but it's troublesome that we're out of money.
And so, we get urges to make quick cash...
だから ついつい手っ取り早く
稼ごうとしてしまうのだが…
Any problem with using these?
（フェイ）
どちらさまも ようござんすね？
Evens!
丁
Evens, is it?
丁ですね？
No, odds after all!
いいや やはり半
半ですね？
Odds, is it?
Yeah... odds.
半だ
Double ace...  Even.
（フェイ）ピンゾロの丁
うえええ あっちゃあ
（エドの寝息）
（エド）ふーん ううん
もう食べられにゃい
I can't eat any more...
Well, it would be easiest for me if you paid up in cash...
（フェイ）
まあ お金で払ってくれれば
こっちとしては一番 楽なんだけど
So, what'll it be?
どうする？
A man does not take back his word!
男に二言はない
（スパイク）うん？
だから やめとけって言ったのに
That's why I told you not to do it...
うっ うう あっりー？
Humans were meant to work and sweat for their money after all.
（ジェット）やはり人間
汗水 流して 働かないといけない
Those that try to get rich quick...
楽して もうけようとか―
...or live at the expense of others...
人の上前をはねて
生きていこうとかいう人間には―
...all get divine retribution somewhere along the way.
いつか天罰が下るのである
That is the lesson...
それが教訓なんだが―
But one thing about humans is that they...
教訓をすぐ忘れるのも
人間の特徴の一つだ
...quickly forget the lessons they just learned.
はーっくしょんっ！
ああー ちきしょう
Dammit.
こんなとこに―
There was a fridge way back here?
冷蔵庫なんてあったか？
"Survival of the fittest" is the law of the land.
（フェイ）
弱肉強食が この世のおきて
だましだまされるのが
人生のことわり
To fool and to be fooled is the reason we live.
I've never had anything good happen to me when I trust others.
他人を信じて
ろくなことのあったためしはないわ
That's the lesson.
それが教訓
How much did you swindle?
いくら だました？
Would you stop saying things that would hurt my reputation?
人聞きの悪いこと
言わないでくれる？
He lost on his own!
向こうが勝手に負けたの
Because he couldn't see through this cheat?
いかさまを見抜けずにか？
It's part of one's skill to see through it.
見抜くのも腕のうちよ
（スパイク）
着るもんくらいは返してやれよ
At least give his clothes back to him.
I'll lend them to him.
貸してあげるわ
Greedy, aren't we?
（スパイク）強欲なこって
It's rough out there in the real world.
勝負の世界ってシビアよね
（スパイク）ああ？
（ジェット）うーん
（スパイク）おい どうした？
Hey, what's up?
（ジェット）何かに かまれた
Something bit me.
（スパイク）うん？
（フェイ）何かって何？
What do you mean, "something"?
はーあ
I-It wasn't a rat!
ん ネズミなんかじゃねえ
見ろよ この首の傷痕
Look at this!  This wound on my neck!
HEY!
おい
This is silly.  It was a waste of time running over here.
（フェイ）ばかばかしい
走って損しちゃった
Spike!  I was bitten around that fridge!
（ジェット）
スパイク そこの冷蔵庫の辺りで
かまれたんだよ
冷蔵庫？
Fridge?
Hmm?  You have a clue?
（ジェット）うん？
何か心当たりがあるのか？
うーん 確か何か…
I'm sure... there was something...
あ 駄目だ　思い出せない
Nope, can't remember.
（ジェット）こんなのが効くのか？
You sure this is gonna work?
The only thing it doesn't work on are nearsightedness and cavities.
（スパイク）効かないのは
近視と虫歯だけだ
Then it works on athlete's foot?
じゃあ 水虫とかも？
Of course.
（スパイク）もちろん
もっと ちゃんとした
化膿(かのう)止めみたいなのはないのか？
Don't you have something more legit that would get rid of sores?
That would be this.
なら これだ
ええっ 化膿止め？
That gets rid of sores?
Yeah.
（スパイク）
そう　こいつを砕いて―
Crush this, and you boil it in 3 cups of water until...
カップ３杯の水を
１杯になるまで煎じて飲むんだ
...the liquid simmers down to 1 cup, and you drink it.
（ジェット）
んー スパイク もうちょっと
こう 違う感じのやつ
Spike, isn't there something more...
...different?
Oh, I got just the thing.
（スパイク）ああ いいのがある
Yeah, gimme that...
（ジェット）おお それよ
えっ ええー
さっきのでいいわ
Gimme what you had before.
Hey...  I'm feeling a lot sicker now...
なあ だんだん気分が
悪くなってきたんだが―
Do I look pale?
顔色 悪くないか？
You're pretty pale to begin with.
（スパイク）もともと悪いからな
What is this awful smell?
（フェイ）何よ このひどい臭い
Herbal medicine.
（スパイク）漢方薬だ
Herbal medicine?  THIS?
漢方薬？ これが？
It smells like you just left a rag that cleaned up spilt milk out to dry!
なんか 牛乳 拭いた雑巾
そのまま干したような臭いね
I think it's more like rotten soybeans.
（スパイク）
あ いやあ どっちかっていうと
納豆の腐ったような臭いだろ
Knock it off!  I have to drink this ya know!
やめろよ！ これから飲むんだぞ
（フェイ）やだ
Oh brother.
（スパイク）おいおい
冗談にしちゃあ…
Hey now, this goes too far for a joke...
It was a rat, right?
（フェイ）ネズミなんでしょ？
騒ぐことないわよ
There's nothing to make a fuss about.
Am I wrong?
違うの？
I have no clue.
（スパイク）分かんねえ
データバンクにはない種類の毒が
回っているようだ
He seems to have gotten some poison that's not in this database.
Looking at similar poisons...
強いて似てるものを挙げると―
Cryptosporidium...
クリプトスポリジウム
...that's not it...
じゃないな
コレラ菌
Cholera?
（ジェット）んん？
Nope...
（スパイク）じゃないし
Ebola virus?
（スパイク）エボラウイルス
（ジェット）いいっ
Nope...
（スパイク）でもないし
（ジェット）あっ ああ
Bifidobacterium?
（スパイク）ビフィズス菌
Not even close.
あ 全然 違うな
What is it?
Ein, you're being noisy.
アイン うるさいよ
I can say for sure that it wasn't an ordinary rat.
ただのネズミじゃないのは確かだ
Hey, keep it quiet.
おい 静かにしてろ
So what is it?
だから何なの？
それは…
Well, it's...
A mysterious space creature!
謎の宇宙生物
（スパイク）ああん？
（フェイ）うん？
Spooky!  The attack of a horrible space creature!
（エド）
怖ーい恐怖の宇宙生物 襲来
そうか そういう可能性も…
Oh yeah, there's that possibility...
Heh...  Yeah, right.
フッ あるわけねえか
Then what is it?
（エド）じゃあ 何？
（スパイク）え ええ？
It's not in the database.
データバンクにないよ？
Yeah...
These base-pairs are weird, too.
この塩基配列も変
You think so?
えっ？ あ そうか？
We've never seen symptoms like this before either.
見たことない症状だし
Other than a space creature, what is it?  What is it?
宇宙生物以外の何？ 何？
Well... um, perhaps something like a rat went through a mutation...
それは その―
ネズミか何かが
突然変異かなんかを起こして―
謎の生物に進化かなんかして―
...and evolved into some mysterious creature...
謎の毒を持つようになったとか
なんとか
...and carried a mysterious poison...
What's that about?
何よ それ　謎の宇宙生物と
大して変わんないじゃない
That isn't too different from the "mysterious space creature" theory!
This is too silly.
ばかばかしい
Aiya... what are we gonna do, Ein?
あやー どうする アイン？
宇宙生物だよ
It's a space creature!
It's spooky!
怖いねー
All right.  This is made to sense heat sources.
（スパイク）
いいか？ こいつは熱源を
感知できるようになってるんだ
It's usually used to find bounties that are hiding.
本来は隠れてる賞金首を捜すのに
使うんだけどな
イヒヒヒヒ
Can you see me?
見えるか？
（エド）おおおーお
All right, I'm gonna test it, so move just like I tell you...
いいか？ テストするから
言ったとおりに動いて
（エド）アイン どこ行くの？
Ein!  Where are you going?
Hey, wait!
HEY!
（スパイク）うん？
That's weird...  Is it broken?
おかしいな　故障か？
Was that response from you?
何だ　今の反応はお前か？
さっきの謎の何とか生物の話だけど
That story you were telling, about some mysterious creature or something-or-other...
Oh, yeah.
（スパイク）ん？ ああ
What happens if you're bitten?
かまれたら 結局どうなるの？
その生物を捕まえてみないと
何とも言えねえが 恐らく…
I can't say for sure until we catch the creature, but I'm going to guess...
...death?
（フェイ）死ぬの？
No... why did it have to be this way?
そんな　どうして こんなことに
I still have a lot to live for...
まだまだ これからってときに
I haven't committed any crimes...
何の罪もないのに
I'm still young and lively...
まだまだ若くて
ピチピチしてるってのに
Lively?
ピチピチ？
ああー なんて かわいそうな私
Oh, poor little me!
（スパイク）おいおい
お前まで一体…
Hey now, why are you getting into this?
August 6th.  Skyday.
（エド）８月６(ろく)日 天曜日
Today, we will go look for the spooky mysterious space creature.
今日は謎の怖ーい宇宙生物を
探しにいきます
Lesson, lesson... if you see a stranger, follow him!
教訓 教訓　知らない人に会ったら
ついて行きましょう
Are you here?
いませんかー？
Are you here, Mr.  Spooky creature?
怖い生物さん 入ってますかー？
いひひ
Ed!  Ein!
エド！ アイン！ おい！
Hey!  This isn't hide-and-seek!
かくれんぼじゃ
ないんだっつーの　ちっ
Exploration, experimentation, exclamation.
（エド）探検 実験 秋田犬
Lights shine bright in the many towns.
八百八町に灯がともる
I will come back alive.  I trust you, Ed.
生きて帰ってくるからな
頼むぜ エド　イヒヒ
ひゅううううううう
ばあああー
あや？
あやや？
Ein!
アイン
Are ya in here?
（スパイク）いないのか？
You're not in here?
いないな？ 返事しろ
Answer me!
ったく
Really...
（アインの悲鳴）
（スパイク）はっ
（スパイク）
アイン エド どうした？
（アインの悲鳴）
Ein, Ed...  What happened?
Ein!
アイン！
Hey, hang in there!
おい しっかりしろ
エドはどうした？
Where's Ed?
簡単に やられやがって
I can't believe it got you this easily.
You're a dog!  Where're your natural instincts?!
犬のくせに
野性ってもんは ないのか？
うわっ わあああああ！
No choice...  Guess I'm going in!
仕方ねえ　やるか
Cruising down Route 66.
（ビバップ号）ルート66を航行中
Approximate cruising time left: 82 hours.
航行時間は あと82時間です
From here, we will enter full autopilot.
これより完全自動航行に入ります
After passing the gate, this ship will automatically land on Mars.
ゲート通過後
火星に自動着陸します
The route cannot be changed after confirmation.
確定後のルート変更はできません
Ed!  You aren't here, are you?  Hey!
エド いないのか？ おい
まさか あいつまで…
Did that thing get her, too?
Don't surprise me!
脅かすな
I've been waiting for ya!
待ちかねたぜ！
Excellent!
上等！
（荒い息）
来いよ 大将！
Come on, you slime!
Got 'im!
もらった！
This thing seems familiar...
こいつ なんかに似てるよな
I guess I shoulda eaten that...
あれ 食っときゃよかったかな
Oh yeah, it should be in the fridge...
そうだ 確か冷蔵庫に…
That was when I remembered everything.
そのとき 俺は全てを思い出した
It was... oh, one year ago.
あれは確か１年ほど前
When I had gotten ahold of a real lobster...
本物のロブスターを
手に入れた俺は―
...I hid it in the fridge in this stockroom...
他のやつに食われないよう―
わざわざこんな倉庫にある冷蔵庫に
隠したんだ
...just so nobody else would eat it.
But I had forgotten about it, and left it in there for a whole year...
しかも それっきり忘れてて
１年間も置きっぱなしだ
I wonder what it looks like in there now...
一体 中が
どんなことになってるやら
（荒い息）
うわっ！ んあ… くそっ
Shit!
Dammit!
しまった！
You shouldn't leave things in the fridge.
（スパイク）冷蔵庫の中の物は
入れっぱなしに しちゃいけない
That is the lesson.
それが教訓だ
うんにゃあ
Sweet bean roll!
おまんじゅう
うーん もう食べられにゃい
Mmm... can't eat anymore...
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
And so... they all passed away.
（エド）というわけで
みんな お亡くなりになりました
Everyone, it was brief, but thanks for your support.
皆様 短い間
ご声援ありがとうございました
This was the last episode.
最終回でした
ご冥福をお祈りします　アーメン
I hope they rest in peace.
Amen.
次回からは
カウガール･エドをお送りしまーす
And starting next episode, we bring you "Cowgirl Ed"!
I'm the main character!
エドが主役だよ ヘヘヘ
Hey, wait a minute!
（スパイク）おい ちょっと待て
（フェイ）あんた 何 勝手なこと
What kinda selfish crap is that?!
Next episode: Jupiter Jazz, Part 1.
（ジェット）次回
「ジュピター･ジャズ（前編）」
There really is another episode!
（スパイク）
次も ちゃんとあるぞ！